Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太と
ひびと
栄光の日 生まれの弟･日々人＞
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
＜日本人初のムーンウォーカー
となった日々人は➡
A lunar accident has left Hibito struggling on the sidelines, suffering from a panic disorder.
月面での事故の影響で
パニック障害となったものの➡
復帰試験に何とか合格した＞
But he's able to pass a test to return to active duty.
Older brother Mutta continues his long quest to the moon,
＜一方 日々人の遥か後ろから➡
月を目指し始めた兄･六太は
ついに月のミッションの➡
having finally been selected as a
backup member for a lunar mission.
バックアップクルーに任命され
訓練を始める＞
And he's about to begin training.
＜しかし 月へ一緒に行く
メンバーは➡
However, his fellow crew members are a unique bunch.
ひと癖も ふた癖もある
連中ばかりだった＞
Hello, this is Eddie Jay.
(ｴﾃﾞｨの声)もしもし｡エディ･Ｊだが｡
[ｹｲﾀｲ](ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ああ どうした？エディ｡
Ah, what is it, Eddie?
なんつ～か あれだ…｡➡
So, I guess...
俺の｢血みどろの魂｣がさ
｢地獄を目指す｣つってんだ｡
My blood-dripping soul says that my destination is hell.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)うん？どういうことだ!?
わかるように言ってくれ｡
What do you mean?
Can you make it easier for me?
(ｴﾃﾞｨ)だからぁ～人生最後に
｢月を目指す｣つってんの｡
I'm saying...
that I'll spend what's left of my life to go to the moon.
I can't get lost in what I'm doing, nothing works out
I don't want these endlessly dull days
I hope I can move on
before the call of freedom drags me away
What's your wish?
I just want some real courage
We all stare doubt in the face, every one of us
Isn't the unpredictability of life the fun of it?
Devote your life to that dream you can't express
Let's go, advance against the wind, our road is long
Embrace the pain of it too
Take a big breath now, and yell
Big Bang! Chase it without fear!
I want to dream so badly it amazes me
There's cowardice in the way of your true wish
Rip that hot veil aside
#94 Exciting Teamwork
No, a helicopter just passed by.
(ﾍﾞﾃｨ)ううん ヘリが通ったのよ｡➡
じゃあ お母さん あとお願いね｡
来週には帰るから｡
Then, talk to you later, Mom.
Look after everything for me.
I'll be back next week...
うん…じゃあね｡
Yeah, bye.
朝はいいわね｡涼しくて｡
In the morning...
it's nice and cool.
時計
スリー！ツー！ワン！➡
Three, two, one...
レゲエ
タイム
Oh Reggae Time！
Reggae time!
時計 ♪～
(ﾌｨﾘｯﾌﾟ)カモーン！
Come on!
時計 ♪～
朝！朝！朝ダンス！
朝！朝！朝ダンス！オーイェイ！
Morning... Morning... Morning dance!
Morning... Morning... Morning dance, yeah!
時計 ♪～
(ﾌｨﾘｯﾌﾟ)朝！朝！朝ダンス！
シンギン！朝！朝！
Morning... Morning... Morning dance!
Morning... Morning...
時計 ♪～
あんた これから毎朝
そ～やって起きる気？
Are you going to do this every morning when you wake up?
時計 ♪～
ヤーオー！
Yeah!
時計 ♪～
カンベンしてほしいわ｡
Give me a break.
時計 ♪～
(ﾌｨﾘｯﾌﾟ)あのな ベティちゃん｡
世の中には➡
Come on, Betty...
In order to live, certain functions must be performed.
時計 ♪～
やらないと死んじゃうものが
あるでしょ？➡
時計 ♪～
｢呼吸｣｢睡眠｣｢食事｣ そして…｡
Breathing.
Sleeping.
Eating.
And...
時計 ♪～
朝ダンス！
Morning dancing!
時計 ♪～
なんば
(南波六太)うわぁ！ふう…ん～！
時計 ♪～
(ﾌｨﾘｯﾌﾟ)朝ダンス！
ハァ ハァ ハァ…ん？
時計 ♪～
なんだ？
What was that?
時計 ♪～
あ…もう７時か｡
It's already seven?
時計 ♪～
Carlo!
カルロ～！朝だぞ～！起きろよ！
Rise and shine...
Time to get up!
時計 ♪～
昨日の夜 飲んでたな…｡
He was drinking last night.
時計 ♪～
(ﾌｨﾘｯﾌﾟ)シンギンタイム！
オー イェイ オー ライ…｡
ハァ…ねえ みんなっ！
Hey, everyone...
Why don't we run together as a group?
もうちょいさ
かたまって走らない!?
ハァ…ねえ ベティも！
Well? How about it, Betty?
バカじゃないの？あんたらの
ペースに合わせてたら➡
Are you an idiot?
If I run at your pace, I won't break a sweat!
走ってることにならないわ！
ヤマン！
Yah, man!
ちょっとフィリップ！
半分踊るの やめようぜ！
Hey, Philippe...
Can't you stop dancing while you run?
いや～ 割とフツーに
走ってるよォ～｡
Well, this is how I run, more or less...
《ん～チクショー
なんてこった…》
Man, why is this happening?
《二日酔いのカルロは
全く走る気ね～し➡
Carlo's hungover and not even trying.
アンディは入～念なストレッチが
いまだ終わらない》
Andy is still stretching...
《朝のジョギングだけで
このバラバラ感…》
We can't even act like a team during a morning jog.
《ど～すんだ？》
How will this work?
(ｶﾙﾛ)いや～いい汗かいたねぇ｡
Yeah, that was an excellent workout...
Now I'm wide awake.
酔いもさめたよ｡
見てよ このキラキラした汗｡
Look at the sparkling sweat on my body.
流星のしずくって呼んでもいいよ｡
Don't you think it's like shooting stars?
あぐ…おせ～んだよ！お前っ！➡
Took you long enough...
なんで後から走り出した
アンディに抜かれてんだよ｡
Andy beat you here, even after starting later.
He didn't beat me...
抜かれたなんて まさか｡
先を譲ったんだよ｡
I let him finish first.
それに…｡
Besides...
(ｶﾙﾛ)朝から あんな獣みたいな
走りを見せられたら➡
After seeing him sprint by like an animal,
引いちゃって戦意も喪失だよ｡
first thing in the morning, I lost my motivation.
あぐっ｡
戦意なんて最初から ね～だろ！
You never had any motivation!
まあまあ 落ち着けよフィリップ｡
Now, now... Calm down, Philippe.
パンケーキが飛び散ってるからさ｡
You're spitting pancake everywhere.
《このクルーには
リーダーがいない…➡
This crew has no leader.
それだけは私も気付いていた》
Even I can see that.
《ならば
自分がリーダーとなって➡
In that case, do I have to play leader, and bring the team together?
みんなを まとめていくしか
ないのではないか？》
《安心と興奮を
同時に与えられるような➡
I must become a leader who can keep everyone motivated and calm.
そんなリーダーに！》
とうとう俺にも
このときがきたか…｡
So it's finally my turn...
みんな！
Everyone!
I realize that as the newest astronaut, I shouldn't be doing this, but this is it.
下っぱの俺が言うのもなんだが…
そういうことだ！
Next, we'll be training to drive the Beetle!
次はビートルの操縦訓練！
さっさと食って片付けるぞ!!
Finish your breakfast, and let's move out!
What do you mean, this is it?
そ～ゆ～ことって
ど～ゆ～こと？
Why are you trying to act like a leader?
何 急にリーダーぶってるんだい｡
君には ぜんぜん似合わないよ｡
It doesn't suit you at all.
あんたねぇ 自分で下っぱを
自覚してんなら➡
If you realize that you're the new kid here, act like it.
下っぱらしくしたらどう？
Uh...
いや…ああ まあ…確かに…｡
Yeah... You're right.
(ｱﾝﾃﾞｨ)ムリすんな｡
Don't try so hard.
ギリギリまで飛ばしても
こんなもんか｡
This is as fast as it'll go...
のんびりなマシンだ｡
It's a slow machine.
それにしても 暑っついわね｡
窓 開かないの？これ｡
It's so damned hot...
Don't these windows open?
いや 開いたら大変でしょ｡
一応 ｢月面｣ローバーだから これ｡
If they opened, we'd be in trouble.
Since we're in a lunar rover.
ねえ その肩のタトゥーさ…｡
Say, about that tattoo on your shoulder...
｢Ｃ｣って書いてあんの？
それとも｢月｣？
Is that a "C"?
Or the moon?
月よ｡
It's the moon.
(ﾍﾞﾃｨ)ていうか
あんま見ないでくれる？➡
And could you stop staring?
I'll knock you down!
張り倒すわよ！
あ はいっ｡
Oh, okay.
Can't I take a peek every 1.8 seconds?
１.８秒区切りで
チラッと見るのもダメ？
(ﾍﾞﾃｨ)バカなの？
Are you an idiot?
If a human can eat good food, drink good wine,
人っていうのはね
おいしいものを食し➡
おいしい酒に酔い そして➡
and surround himself with beauty,
美しいものに
囲まれてさえいれば➡
それはマキシマムな
ハッピーライフなんだよ｡
he'll have the happiest life imaginable.
つまりね…
俺はベティと乗りたかった｡
In other words...
I wanted to ride with Betty.
俺も お前以外なら
今 ハッピーなんだけどな！
If I weren't stuck with you, I'd be happy right now.
《独り…》
I'm alone.
Don't you have anyone to ride with, Andy?
一緒に乗る相手がいないのか？
アンディ｡
ふ～暑っついわね 外も｡
It's just as hot outside.
(ｴﾃﾞｨ)おかえり～｡
Welcome back.
ど～だった？そいつの乗り心地は｡
So how was the ride?
エディ！
Eddie...
I wanted to take the Beetle for a spin...
俺も乗ってみたかったんだよな～
ビートル｡
最近 月に興味あってな
俺も仲間に入れてくれ｡
I've gotten an itch to go to the moon.
Let me join in.
《この人は…！》
That's...
よぉ！兄弟｡
Hey, Brother...
初めまして！ナンバ･ムッタです！
It's an honor to meet you!
I'm Nanba Mutta!
(ｼﾞｮｰｼﾞ)新メンバーを紹介しよう｡
Let me introduce the new member.
黙れ！お前ら｡
Stop talking, people!
Starting today, veteran astronaut Eddie Jay will be joining in this training as the sixth astronaut.
今日からベテラン飛行士
エディ･Ｊが➡
この訓練に加わることになった
６人目のメンバー｡
お前らサブクルーのリーダーだ！
He will be the leader of the sub crew.
Hey, hey...
まあまあ リーダーっつっても
俺も月は初心者だ｡君らと同じ｡
You can call me the leader, but when it comes to the moon, I'm a beginner.
Just like the rest of you.
だから初めて月に立った時
その喜びも君らと同じだろう｡
So when I finally stand on the moon,
I'll be just as thrilled as you will.
ともに月に立とう｡
Let's go to the moon together.
It only took a moment for everything to click.
《一瞬にして わかってしまった｡
リーダーというのは やはり➡
A leader is someone who can keep everyone inspired and calm.
安心と興奮を同時にくれる》
《この人は俺達のリーダーだ》
And this man was our leader!
＜中学･高校と問題児ばかりが
集められたクラスには➡
In middle and high school,
they typically assign extremely strict teachers
決まって鬼のようなスパルタ教師
が担任についたもんだが…＞
to the classes that are full of troublemakers.
But for some reason,
＜問題児ばかりが集められた
我がクルーには➡
どういうわけか
温和なリーダーがやってきた＞
our crew of troublemakers was assigned a friendly leader.
お～？なんだ ありゃ｡
What's she doing?
She's always so fast!
速ぇ～なぁ 今日も｡
Ｆｕｕ！
あ…エディ うちのクルーって
こんな感じなんだよ｡
Yeah, Eddie...
Our crew's always like this.
ハハ…なるほど ハハ｡➡
I see.
いいねぇ ワクワクしてきた｡
I like it...
I'm getting excited.
It seems they have a long way to go...
(教官)やはり まだまだと
いった印象ですな｡➡
仲が悪いというほどではないが➡
I wouldn't say they aren't getting along,
ここまで それぞれが
まれ
自分勝手なクルーは稀ですよ｡
but it's rare to see crew members act so completely independently.
(教官)まとまりのなさは
ピカイチだな｡
They're the least organized bunch I've ever seen.
At this rate, that crew will never be assigned to a mission.
(教官)このままだと このチームで
ミッションに➡
アサインされることは
ないんじゃないですか？
Hold on... Their leader just arrived.
まあ リーダーのエディが
来たところだ｡
もう少し様子を見ようじゃないか｡
We should wait and see what he can do.
Thanks, Betty!
ありがとう ベティ！
いっただきま～す！
Let's eat!
うっ！辛ぇ～っ!!
Hot!
うっ！なんだ これ!?➡
What the hell?
コショウの味しか しねぇ!!
It's like I'm eating a bottle of pepper!
自分でも分かってるから｡
私 料理は苦手なの｡
I know, okay?
I'm a bad cook.
おいしくないなら おいしくない
ってハッキリ言いなさいよ｡
If it tastes bad, just say so.
Uh, well...
あっ いや まあ ちょっと
辛かったかな｡
It's a little spicy...
Only a little.
ほんのちょっと｡
一週間分のコショウ入ってるよ｡
これ!!
You dumped a week's worth of pepper in this!
もっぺん言ってみなさいよ｡
あんたら｡
Why don't you repeat that?
そのアゴ はずすわよ｡
I'll dislocate your jaw!
《俺も含まれてる》
Did she mean me, too?
If you have any complaints, address them to Eddie.
文句あるならエディに言うことね｡
We could be eating pre-made meals,
今まで通り簡易食品で済ませれば
いいところを➡
わざわざ順番に手料理を作ろう
なんていうのがどうかしてるのよ｡
but he decided we should cook instead.
He's got issues.
その方が楽しいじゃないか｡
Now, now...
It's more fun this way.
夕食は俺が作るよ｡
I'll make dinner.
I'll eat anything that doesn't have pepper...
小声 コショウを
使わないヤツを お願い｡
《まあ…早めにベティの料理の
味を知ってて よかった》
Well, it's a good thing we got Betty's cooking out of the way now.
Thanks, Eddie.
《ありがとう エディ》
If I hadn't found out till we were on the moon...
《これ…月面で初体験だったら》
⦅辛ぇ～!!⦆
Hot!
《ちょっとした事件だ》
...that could've been quite an accident.
(カルロ)ただいま～ さて朝食を
いただこう｡
I'm back...
Okay, time to eat.
(ﾌｨﾘｯﾌﾟ)おせ～よ！
あれ？➡
Took you long enough.
Oh?
This is more food than I usually get.
なんか多いね 今日｡
全部 食えよ｡
Eat it all.
《罰だ！遅れた罰！》
It's punishment! Punishment for tardiness!
(カルロ)うおあ～！
ヒューストーン
え～ こちら月着陸船アルタイル｡
Houston!
This is the lunar module Altair...
It looks like we're way off on our landing.
予定の着地地点を
大きくズレた模様｡
This is Houston.
こちらヒューストン 了解した｡
We read you.
そちらの全員が
確認できない状態だ｡
We are unable to confirm your current position.
そこから見える景色を
説明してくれ｡
Tell us what you can see.
それを こっちでスケッチする｡
We'll attempt to draw a sketch.
(通信:ﾌｨﾘｯﾌﾟ)了解！
Roger that.
じゃあ 頼むわよ｡
Okay, go for it.
Let's see...
ええっとね～ １２時の方向は
岩のね 固まりのね➡
At twelve o'clock, there's a rock?
A bunch of rocks...
山がね ボーン！ボーン！と｡➡
And mountains going, "Wham! Wham!"
And another "Wham!"
もう１コ ボーン！と｡
Wham.
ボン…｡
そんなバカみたいな説明で
わかるわけないでしょ!?
No one understands that idiotic explanation!
ちゃんと絵に描けるように
伝えなさいよ！
Give us a description we can actually draw!
砂岩のかたまり…がある｡
There's a pile of sand.
うん…ジグザグだ｡
It zigzags...
Zigzags?
(通信:ﾍﾞﾃｨ)ジグザグ!?
いや…ギザギザだ｡
Wait.
It's jagged.
If you guys had really had an accident, you'd be stranded for the rest of your lives.
これが本物の事故なら
一生 迷子だぞ｡お前ら｡
そうだね～
美しいシマ模様の地層だよ｡
Let's see...
There's a lovely striped cliff.
形は静かな朝に ゆらめく
穏やかな波のようだよ｡
It reminds me of waves rolling softly in the morning.
こんがりと焼けた
夏の肌のような層の間に➡
Alternating lines, dark as a summer tan
かれん
可憐な乙女の白い肌を思わせる➡
and pale as a fair maiden's skin.
たおやかで美麗な
地層が流れているよ｡
It's a beautiful sight to behold.
(通信:ｼﾞｮｰｼﾞ)長いな！
That was long.
(ベティ)何あんた うまいわね｡
Wow, you're good at this.
Huh?
え？そ そう？
Really?
But it looks like a mess because I followed their instructions.
でもムチャクチャだよ
言われた通りに描いたら｡
ふ～ん｡
Hey... Don't look!
ちょっと！見んじゃないわよ！
ええ～！走るの!?これから？
Eh?! You want us to go running now?
Now, now.
まあまあ 明日から朝のジョギング
の趣向を変えようと思ってな｡
I'm thinking about changing up our morning jog tomorrow.
今日は そのリハーサルだと
思ってくれ｡
Think of this as a rehearsal.
たった２キロだけだから｡
どう変えるの？
We're only running two kilometers.
What kind of change do you mean?
カンタン｡
It's simple.
キャンプの周りを
グルグル回るのをやめるんだ｡
We won't be running in circles around the camp.
もっとワクワクするやり方がある｡
We can make it more exciting and fun.
不服か？ハハハ 了解は得てるよ｡
Not happy?
I've already got permission.
明日の朝からは こうやるんだ｡
Here's what we'll do tomorrow morning.
First, the six of us will get in this truck,
まず６人全員が この車に乗って➡
キャンプ地から数キロ離れた
どこだか分からない場所で➡
and they'll drop us off at an unknown location a few kilometers from camp.
降ろされる｡そこから
ジョギング開始｡➡
We'll head for our camp,
keeping a pace so that we arrive at a predetermined time.
キャンプに向かって決められた
時刻ちょうどに着くように走る｡➡
We can't arrive early or late.
目標時刻より早すぎても
遅すぎてもダメ｡
Simple, right?
カンタンだな｡
And I'm the only one allowed to wear a watch.
ちなみに時計を持っていいのは
俺だけ｡
う…うむ｡
さあ 着いたぞ ２キロ地点だ｡
Okay, here we are...
Two kilometers away.
今 ２０時３０分｡
目標時刻は ２０時５０分だ！
It's 8:30 now.
Our target time is 8:50!
なるほど！
《さすがエディ｡➡
I get it.
Eddie's good.
これなら…！》
In this situation...
さあ いくか！
Okay, let's go.
(エディ)スタート！
Start!
ハハハ…あれえ？
どうした～ みんな｡
Oh?
What's wrong, guys?
もっと いつもみたいに
バラバラに走っても いいんだぜ！
You're free to spread out like usual!
The starlight illuminates my future, it's wow... truth
It's 3 AM, and I dream awake
With no idea of my future
only impatience consumes me
I have a thorn in my heart that won't allow me to lose to him
I'm walking a path of thorns I made for myself
But I won't forget the love I found
And I won't forget the ones close to me
I realized you cannot live your life alone
The starlight illuminates my future, and we are all shooting stars
My holy wishes turn all our sad lies into something better
Our orbits have gotten separated,
but I'm fine if you are close
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#95 Our Future
Before our training in the desert ends, Betty reveals her motivation.
＜砂漠での最後の訓練を前に
ﾍﾞﾃｨの秘めた思いが明らかに＞
Mutta's the only one here who doesn't know Betty's history.
(ｴﾃﾞｨ)＜まだ ベティのことで➡
ムッタだけが知らないことが
あるだろ＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Our Future"
I have an adorable son.
(ﾍﾞﾃｨ)＜私には
可愛い可愛い息子がいる＞